A Guide to the Virginia War History Commission, 1915-1931
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records, 1915-1931
Library of Virginia
37219, 28390, 33311 and 28057
121.04 cubic feet
Virginia War History Commission
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from Virginia War History Commission, date unknown (accession 37219 and 28390).
Transferred from the University of Virginia, 2 November 1988 (accession 33311).
Gift of Mrs. Frances H. Paulette, 27 June 1973 (accession 28057).
Historical Information
On 7 January 1919, Governor Westmoreland Davis created the Virginia War History Commission whose goal was "to complete an accurate and complete history of Virginia's military, economic and political participation in the World War." The Commission consisted of sixteen leading citizens appointed by the governor including: Reverend Collins Denny, Brigadier General Jo Lane Stern, Adjutant General of Virginia, Douglas Southall Freeman, editor of the Richmond News-Leader, State Librarian Henry R. McIlwaine, and Colonel Charles R. Keiley, Executive Secretary of the Second Virginia Council of Defense. Arthur Kyle Davis, president of Southern Female College in Petersburg, was named chairman of the commission. The commission served without compensation and from January to September 1919 relied on the Second Virginia Council of Defense for financial support. Subsequently, on the governor's recommendation, the General Assembly appropriated $10,000 on 10 September 1919 to enable the commission to discharge its duties. Financial support was continued from 1919 to 1927 by annual appropriations.
Upon his appointment as chairman, Arthur Kyle Davis immediately implemented his plan for preserving Virginia's war records. On 6 August 1918, during the presentation of a service flag by the United Daughters of the Confederacy at the Sussex County Court House, Davis proposed that the people of each community in Virginia preserve the records and activities of their activities. Local branches of the Commission, consisting of a chairman and two associates, were established in Virginia's 100 counties and 21 cities, to collect records of their community's military and civilian activities. The Commission created a fifteen topic outline of subjects to be included in the statewide history. Some of the topics included Virginians of Distinguished Service, Virginia Churches, Economic Conditions, Red Cross and War Letters and Diaries. An editor assigned to each topic would then write the narrative. This material would then form the basis of the Commission's proposed four volume history of Virginia during the World War.
Unfortunately, poor or non-existent leadership by the local branches, apathy, and a lack of time and money hampered the Commission's collection of war records. The quantity and quality of records collected varied widely. In 1921 the Commission published four War History Supplements in the Virginia Magazine of History and Biography listing the source material collected by the local branches. Very few records were collected after 1921 and interest in the Commission's work quickly waned.
In addition to the magazine supplements, the Virginia War History Commission published seven volumes. Volumes I-IV were summaries of source material compiled by the commission. These volumes included lists of distinguished soldiers, newspaper clippings chronicling the war, a guide to war letters, diaries and editorials, and a series of sketches of civilian war agencies. Volumes V-VII were specific chronicles of Virginia wartime activities. Volumes include military unit histories and locality histories that describe the location of the communities, their resources, pre-war conditions, economic conditions, relief and institutional war work. Preliminary manuscripts for a narrative history of Virginia's role in the war were prepared as well. By June 1928 all of the source materials and manuscripts were transferred to the Virginia State Library, but, because of various difficulties, the narrative history was never published. The War History Commission submitted their last annual report to the Governor and General Assembly on 18 January 1928 and had ceased all operations by July 1928.
Scope and Content Information
The Virginia War History Commission Records are housed in 302 boxes and 5 oversize boxes. The collection is arranged into nineteen (19) series. Series have been designated for: I. Individual Service Records (Questionnaires); II. Virginians of Distinguished Service; III. Virginia Military Organizations; IV. Virginia's Camps and Cantonments; V. Virginia Schools and Colleges; VI. County Source Material; VII. City Source Material; VIII. Selective Service and Volunteers; IX. Virginia War Diaries and Incidents; X. Scrapbooks; XI. Office Files; XII. First Virginia Council of Defense; XIII. Virginia Agricultural Council of Safety; XIV. Second Virginia Council of Defense; XV. Margaret Ethel Kelley Kern Papers; XVI. H.R. McIlwaine Papers; XVII. Miscellaneous Records; XVIII. Lynchburg City Committee Records; and XIX. Prince Edward County Committee Records. These records include books, broadsides, checks, citations, correspondence, diaries, invitations, invoices, magazines, maps, military records, minute books, newspapers, newspaper clippings, photographs, post cards, press releases, programs, publications, questionnaires, receipts, reports, scrapbooks, sheet music, song books, and telegrams. These records document Virginia's participation in World War I and its attempt to preserve records of that participation.
Following is a brief overview of the collection. A more in-depth description of the collection can be found in the Series and Subseries level descriptions. It is recommended that the researcher read the Series level scope and content notes thoroughly before accessing the collection.
The experiences of Virginians in the military during the war are well documented throughout the collection. Information on the background and experiences of individual soldiers (and a few nurses) is recorded in the questionnaires (Series I and Series II). Additional information concerning soldiers' views of the war may be found in letters and diaries (Series VI, Series VII, Series IX and Series X).
Of note to the military historian, the collection includes histories of Virginia units including Home Guards and the history of Virginia military cantonments including Camp Humphreys and Camp Lee (Series III, Series IV and Series VIII).
For researchers interested in home front activities, there are some noteworthy records. Propaganda, food and fuel conservation, health and morality issues are highlighted in the records of the First Virginia Council of Defense (Series XII), Virginia Agricultural Council of Safety (Series XIII) and Second Virginia Council of Defense (Series XIV). Additional records of note include material on churches and schools (Series V, Series VI and Series VII).
The collection contains extensive information on the activities of the Virginia War History Commission including personnel, local branches and publications. (Series XI).
Volumes were housed in boxes for better protection. Oversized items are filed in 5 boxes. Oversize items, which were part of a regular sized filing unit, were removed from their respective folders. In their place, separation notices list the item(s) removed and the oversize box and folder number to which they have been removed. For location and content list of oversize folders see list at the end of the finding aid.
Organization
The collection is organized into the following nineteen series:
Organization
Series I: Individual Service Records (Questionnaires), 1919-1924 (bulk 1919-1921
Series II: Virginians of Distinguished Service, 1922-1925
Series III: Virginia Military Organizations, ca. 1917-1922, 1925
Series IV: Virginia's Camps and Cantonments, ca. 1917-1919
Series V: Virginia Schools and Colleges, 1919-1922
Series VI: County Source Material, 1919-1927
Series VII: City Source Material, 1919-1927
Series VIII: Selective Service and Volunteers, 1917-1921, 1925
Series IX: Virginia War Diaries and Incidents, 1915-1922 (bulk 1917-1919)
Series X: Scrapbooks, 1915-1923
Series XI: Office Files, 1917-1927
Series XII: First Virginia Council of Defense, 1917-1918
Series XIII: Virginia Agricultural Council of Safety, 1917-1918
Series XIV: Second Virginia Council of Defense, 1917-1921, 1923-1924
Series XV: Margaret Ethel Kelley Kern Papers, 1917-1925, 1928
Series XVI: H.R. McIlwaine Papers, 1919, 1921, 1928-1929 and 1931
Series XVII: Miscellaneous Records, 1917-1921 (accession 28390)
Series XVIII: Lynchburg City Committee Records, 1919-1921 (accession 33311)
Series XIX: Prince Edward County Committee Records, 1919-1920 (accession 28057)
Contents List
- S eries I: Individual Service Records (Questionnaires), 1919-1924 (bulk 1919-1921)
  The Individual Service Records (Questionnaires) series is housed in 20 boxes and is arranged into two (2) subseries. Subseries have been designated for Counties and Cities. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by locality and there under alphabetically by name of soldier (with white and non-white questionnaires further segregated). This series consists of questionnaires completed by soldiers who served from Virginia during World War I or their next-of-kin. The four page questionnaire records personal and military data. The first page records personal information including the full name of the soldier, date and place of birth, name of mother and father (and their places of birth), race, religious affiliation, names of wife and children, fraternal orders and college fraternities, education, occupation prior to entering the service, name of employer, residence before and after time in service, and present home address. The second and third pages records military information including, date of induction, rank, military branch and ID number, military company, regiment and division; where trained or stationed, port of embarkation and debarkation, experiences in action, citations for and details of distinguished services, details of any injuries (or death), and occupation after the war. The fourth page contains several questions designed to elicit information about how the war affected the serviceman and how he perceived his experiences during the war. The questions deal with the effect of disabilities upon occupation and employment, the serviceman's attitude toward military service, the mental and physical effects of United States camp experiences and of overseas experiences, how the experience affected his religious beliefs, and the effects of all of these experiences as contrasted with his state of mind before the war. Nurses submitted a two page questionnaire asking similar questions. Photographs often accompany the questionnaires.
  This series is arranged into two subseries. Subseries have been designated for Counties and Cities.
  - Subseries A: Counties
    - Accomack County
      - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - B (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - B (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - C (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - C (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - D (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - E-F (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - G (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - H (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - I-K (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - L (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - M (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - N-O (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - P (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - R (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - S (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - T (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - W-Y (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Accomack County (Colored)
      - A-B (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - C-G (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - H-R (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - S (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - T-Y (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Albemarle County
      - A-D (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - E-J (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - K-P (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - R-Y (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Albemarle County (Colored)
      - D-Y (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Albemarle County
      - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Alexandria County
      - Allen, Herbert Osborne (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Alleghany County
      - A-B (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - C (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - D-J (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - K-L (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - M-R (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - S-Y (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Alleghany County (Colored)
      - B-J (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Alleghany County
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Amelia County
      - A-Z (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Amherst County
      - A-Z (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Appomattox County
      - A-W (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Appomattox County (Colored)
      - A-W (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Alexandria County
      - A-W (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Augusta County
      - A-W (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Augusta County (Colored)
      - Saunders, Charley (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Augusta County
      - Miscellaneous Records (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Bath County
      - B-V (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous Records (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bedford County
      - A-F (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - G-K (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - L-P (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - P-W (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Bedford County (Colored)
      - B-W (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Bedford County
      - Miscellaneous Records (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Bland County
      - A-M (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - N-S (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - T-W (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Bland County (Colored)
      - S (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Botetourt County
      - B-W (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Brunswick County
      - A-C (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - D-K (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - L-R (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - S-W (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Brunswick County (Colored)
      - A-H (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - J-W (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Buchanan County
      - B (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Buckingham County
      - A-B (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - C (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - D-G (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - H-J (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - K-M (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - N-P (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - R-S (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - T-W (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Buckingham County (Colored)
      - A-B (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - C-F (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - G-P (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - R-W (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Campbell County
      - B-W (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Caroline County
      - A-V (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Caroline County (Colored)
      - G-Y (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Caroline County
      - Miscellaneous Records (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Carroll County
      - A-W (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Charles City County
      - A-S (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Charlotte County
      - A-W (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Chesterfield County
      - B-L (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - M-W (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Chesterfield County (Colored)
      - B-W (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Chesterfield County
      - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Clarke County
      - A-C (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - D-G (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - H-M (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - P-W (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Clarke County (Colored)
      - B-W (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Craig County
      - F-K (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Culpeper County
      - A-E (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - F-L (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - M-S (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - T-W (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Culpeper County (Colored)
      - P (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Culpeper County
      - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Cumberland County
      - A-K (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - P-W (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Cumberland County (Colored)
      - A-C (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - D-M (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - N-W (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Cumberland County
      - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Dickenson County
      - A-B (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - C-D (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - E-H (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - K-M (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - N-R (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - s (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - S-Y (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Dinwiddie County
      - A-P (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - R-Z (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Dinwiddie County (Colored)
      - B-W (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Elizabeth City County
      - A-B (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - C-E (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - F-G (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - H-K (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - L-R (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - S (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - T-Z (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Elizabeth City County (Colored)
      - A-W (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Essex County
      - A-T (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Fairfax County
      - A-L (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - M-W (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Fairfax County (Colored)
      - H (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Fauquier County
      - A-E (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - F-L (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - M-W (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Fauquier County (Colored)
      - A-W (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Fauquier County
      - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Floyd County
      - A-W (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Fluvanna County
      - B-S (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Fluvanna County (Colored)
      - C-S (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Franklin County
      - B-T (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Frederick County
      - C-W (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Giles County
      - A-B (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - C-D (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - E-G (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - H-J (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - K-O (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - P-R (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - S-T (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - V-Y (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Giles County (Colored)
      - A-W (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Giles County
      - Unidentified Photograph (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Gloucester County
      - A-J (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - K-W (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Gloucester County (Colored)
      - B-Y (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Goochland County
      - B-H (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - J-W (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Goochland County (Colored)
      - A-F (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - G-W (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Goochland County
      - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Grayson County
      - A-B (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - B (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - C (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - C (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - D-F (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - G (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - H (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - H (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - I-K (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - L-M (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - M-O (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - P (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - P (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - R (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - S (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - T-V (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - W (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - W (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Y (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Grayson County (Colored)
      - B-V (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Grayson County
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Greene County
      - A-Z (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Greensville County
      - B-H (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - H-W (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Greensville County (Colored)
      - A-Y (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Halifax County
      - A-Z (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Halifax County (Colored)
      - M (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Hanover County
      - A-Z (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Henrico County
      - A-W (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Henrico County (Colored)
      - B (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Henrico County
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Henry County
      - A-Z (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Highland County
      - A-E (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - F-H (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - J-R (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - T-W (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Highland County (Colored)
      - C-S (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Highland County
      - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Isle of Wight County
      - A-Z (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Isle of Wight County (Colored)
      - C-J (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - James City County
      - A-Z (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - James City County (Colored)
      - A-W (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - King and Queen County
      - A-Z (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - King and Queen County (Colored)
      - A-Z (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - King William County
      - A-Z (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - King William County (Colored)
      - A-W (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Lancaster County
      - A-B (Box 6, Folder 34)
      - C (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - D-F (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - G (Box 6, Folder 37)
      - H-K (Box 6, Folder 38)
      - L-O (Box 6, Folder 39)
      - P-S (Box 6, Folder 40)
      - T-W (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Lancaster County (Colored)
      - A-W (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Lee County
      - A-Z (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Loudoun County
      - N-T (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Letters (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Louisa County
      - A-C (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - D-H (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - J-P (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - R-W (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Louisa County (Colored)
      - A-G (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - H-J (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - K-R (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - S-W (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Lunenburg County
      - A-W (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Lunenburg County (Colored)
      - A-G (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - H-T (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Madison County
      - J-S (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Mathews County
      - A-G (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - H-W (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Mathews County (Colored)
      - B-W (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Mecklenburg County
      - A-C (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - D-J (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - K-P (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - R-W (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Mecklenburg County (Colored)
      - A-L (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - M-Z (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Middlesex County
      - B-S (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Montgomery County
      - A-W (Box 7, Folder 26)
      - Miscellaneous Records (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Nansemond County
      - B-W (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Nelson County
      - B-W (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - New Kent County
      - H (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Norfolk County
      - A-C (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - D-G (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - H (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - J-O (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - P-S (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - T-Z (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk County (Colored)
      - A-J (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - L-Y (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Northampton County
      - A-C (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - D-G (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - H-O (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - P-Z (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Northampton County (Colored)
      - M-T (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Northumberland County
      - B-T (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Nottoway County
      - A-Ba (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Be-B (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - C (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - D-E (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - F-G (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - H (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - I-L (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - M-P (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - R (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - S (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - T-V (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - W-Z (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Nottoway County (Colored)
      - A-B (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - C (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - D-E (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - F-Foster (Box 8, Folder 25)
      - Fowlkes-G (Box 8, Folder 26)
      - H-I (Box 8, Folder 27)
      - J (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - K-O (Box 8, Folder 29)
      - P-R (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - S (Box 8, Folder 31)
      - T-Williams (Box 8, Folder 32)
      - Willis-Z (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Orange County
      - "Volunteers from Orange County and Men Sent to Camp from Orange County" (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - A-C (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - D-H (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - I-L (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - M-Q (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - R-S (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - T-W (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Orange County (Colored)
      - B-W (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Page County
      - A-L (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - M-Z (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Unidentified photograph found in box containing questionnaires from Patrick through Scott Counties (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Patrick County
      - A-Z (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Pittsylvania County
      - A-B (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - C-F (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - G-M (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - N-S (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - T-Z (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Powhatan County
      - A-Z (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Powhatan County (Colored)
      - C-W (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Prince Edward County